<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
	<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
	<channel>
	<title>Procedural Visuality</title>
	<link>https://phd.thgie.ch</link>
	<description>This dissertation project inquires the complex interplay of code and visuality in digital games. The research focus lies on early games attributed to Switzerland and their visuality, mainly the the image seen on screen.</description>
	<atom:link href='https://phd.thgie.ch/feed.xml' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml' />
	
<item>
		<title>Corpus, corpora and visual methodologies</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-03-10.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-03-10</pubDate>
        <description>Since I am the graphics-person, I'm also collecting images, of course. I try to do as many screenshots as necessary and scrape the internet for additional material.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Looking back at the Games & Literature Conference</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-07-05.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-07-05</pubDate>
        <description>The Games & Literature conference at the German Literature Archive in Marbach was intense. I counted 30 talks on the program, from which I attended 25 and gave one together with Eugen Pfister.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Diss-Storming Session</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-03-31.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-03-31</pubDate>
        <description>I have a basic assumption after a rather broad reading of texts. There seems to be an invisible rift between the research image of the video game and its material base, a border between the visuality and technology.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>It's summer time: readings, corpora and other updates</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-07-20.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-07-20</pubDate>
        <description>It's summer and I can finally concentrate on all things related to my dissertation project. On the agenda is playing video games, working on a representation of masculinity in old games' subproject, working on my Image Corpus, and, of course, getting some reading is done.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Autumn – Mid-Semester</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-10-23.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-10-23</pubDate>
        <description>As expected, the study semester is taking a toll on time, energy and focus. It seems easier, and more relevant, than last semester. Besides that, I feel that the productivity from the summer came to a halt.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Literature</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-02-04.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-02-04</pubDate>
        <description>After the wonderful kick-off, which cost me a lot of social energy (worth every unit), I got some input on literature.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Kick-off</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-02-01.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-02-01</pubDate>
        <description>Starting December 2022, I began with my literature review. Being only vaguely familiar with analyzing video games, that was an obvious way to start.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Images in Social Media Research</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-02-11.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-02-11</pubDate>
        <description>I took part in the online-workshop: Images in Social Media Research.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Close Reading the VICE Source Code</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-06-20.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-06-20</pubDate>
        <description>Today I'm attempting to close read the code base of the VICE emulator. I already made some attempts at this through going into the source code author's comments.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Emulation</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-02-15.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-02-15</pubDate>
        <description>The last two weeks I was playing a few video games by Golden Gate Crew as well as Linel. They were all developed and published for the Amiga system. In order to play them, I had to work with an emulator.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Post-Summer – Pre-semester</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-09-09.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-09-09</pubDate>
        <description>I was on a two weeks vacation in August and didn't care much about my journal. Still, a lot of things continued to become and manifest.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Distant reading and computing history</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-05-29.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-05-29</pubDate>
        <description>I have a few first thoughts on treating a code repository as source for distant reading methods.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>DHCH 2023, accuracy in visuality and the OpenRefine-Wikidata combo</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-06-16.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-06-16</pubDate>
        <description>As the title implies this will be a larger entry. I'd love to briefly cover my participation at the DHCH 2023, the summer school/conference of the Swiss Digital Humanities.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Another Proposal Sketch</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2022-09-30.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2022-09-30</pubDate>
        <description>Another sketch for a dissertation proposal…</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Proposal Sketch</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2022-09-24.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2022-09-24</pubDate>
        <description>A sketch for a dissertation proposal.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>VICE and Voyant Tools</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-05-07.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-05-07</pubDate>
        <description>I talked with Moritz Mähr about how to approach treating a code base as a text corpus, and he recommended to give Voyant Tools a shot.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Dissertation and Project Contemplation</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-02-28.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-02-28</pubDate>
        <description>As a preparation for a first dissertation meeting with my supervisor, I note my expectations, thoughts and questions here.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>Memo on Videospiele by Jakob Birken</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-04-08.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-04-08</pubDate>
        <description>I've finished reading Jakob Birken's Videospiele and found it to be a good primer. Some interesting topics got touched, but never dug deep.</description>
        </item>
<item>
		<title>March Reflection on Dissertation Topic</title>
        <link>https://phd.thgie.ch/journal/2023-03-23.html/</link>
        <pubDate>2023-03-23</pubDate>
        <description>Right now I do feel a bit lost with my dissertation. But I'm sure that's how it has to be right now. I had a meeting with my supervisor last week that was very giving in terms on how to go forwards. The most important take-away was, that I should speak to all my disciplines.</description>
        </item>
</channel>
	</rss>
